[Music]
hello this is simon hyatt i'm the
contributing editor of asian business
review magazine
today i'm presenting the asian
experience awards recognizing the most
meaningful and ingenious experience
initiatives in the region for 2021.
today i'm joined by vijay madhevan the
chief executive officer of prudential
laos
prudential has won the last employee
experience award of the year for life
insurance in the asian experience awards
2021.
vijay thank you so much for joining us
today and congratulations on your award
win
thank you simon this is really humbling
and i'm absolutely delighted to
receive this award on behalf of my team
this award belongs to them for their
hard work and dedication vijay tell us a
little bit more about the learning and
development initiatives launched by
prudential laos for its employees
how did employee engagement increase
after their launch well simon we live in
a world where we have opportunities to
leapfrog
against the face of disruption
so in prudential now given the nascency
of this market there was an opportunity
for us to get to the customers with
speed
so we introduced new ways of working
on the concepts of agile
but we also wanted to bring out the
ideas of the staff and we also and so we
rolled out founders mentality by bain
and company as a minimum competence for
all new staff who join our company in
launching the founder mentality program
do you also aim to impact employee
retention well simon it goes beyond just
retention it also covers employees
personal growth
founder's mentality by bailing company
embraces three overarching principles
an insurgent mindset
frontline obsession
and an owner's mindset where each
resource is fed as if it's their own
this obviously creates ownership
a sense of accountability but most
importantly
staff feel that they are creating a
larger impact to the customers in the
community around them vijay can you give
us an idea of the types of projects
proposed under the founder mentality
program
what were the factors that contributed
to the progress and completion of these
projects well that's a very interesting
question simon and you know there's
plenty to say
from the founders mentality program we
created what we call micro battles or
sandboxing projects
some 40 sandbox projects were developed
this past year
of which 10 became
live and were rolled out to the market
well
a couple of examples come to mind and i
think here we're very proud
to talk about the covet care freemium
that we rolled out both in april and in
september
for the law market based on that
principles of agile our first run was
done in eight days and we rolled out and
we covered some 13 000 customers
in september we did the same thing but
we were able to bring the same solutions
to the market just in a matter of three
days
and we did twice the amount within the
same period
and this is creative because there is a
sense of ownership and urgency and
people enjoy the way we work with daily
stand-up meetings and ideas being thrown
and continuous iteration of the project
it also gives me great pleasure to just
tell you simon that two days ago we
rolled out a very simple bite-sized
product
that covered vaccination side effects
at less than a dollar u.s for five
months of cover and it's been received
with great positivity from the public
now this gives us pride and motivation
to do more for them because of the speed
at which we can deliver solutions
strategy development usually originates
from senior management or executive
leadership
why is it important for prudential laos
to engage new joiners in developing
corporate strategy
good question simon and
here
our staff are also our customers
they have experiences as consumers
across a variety of services and
products
and with a wider pool of experience we
bring in more ideas
and it creates a sense of enablement
during the half year we had a
three-day hot house where we brought in
a number of our managers and staff at
including young management trainees
and the number of ideas actually helped
us to streamline the three focused areas
for the coming years
so it's
simple yet it gives us enough depth to
take the business forward and be able to
experiment within those pillars
and create a difference to our community
vijay what does winning in the inaugural
asian experience awards 2021 mean for
you and your team
exhilaration
excitement motivation
these are words that come to mind but
there's many more i can articulate but
to us it validates the work we've been
doing to try to bring people into the
forefront of our innovation
and delivery of services that are
world-class to our customers
growth is hard to do but maintaining
growth at speed
is a continuous challenge
and we believe with this award it opens
up
more ideas from our staff on how we can
stay ahead of the game
and be of value and service to our
stakeholders so absolutely delighted
simon vijay madivan thank you so much
for being with us today and
congratulations once again on your award
win
thank you simon pleasure's mine
[Music]